# **Eugenia PAPAGEORGIOU**

Chemin de Beau - Soleil, 5 - 1206 Geneva Greek-Swiss nationality 22.05.1968 Married, 2 children +41 76 450 06 83



 $ep@eugenia-papageorgiou.ch \ / \ https://www.linkedin.com/in/epapageorgiou$ 

Have worked mainly within the banking sector as a **Programmer Analyst** and a **Systems and Accounting Controller.** Across diverse industries, have gained skills and knowledge in the areas of information technology, project management, finance, accounting and internal controls.

Studies in System Programming, Information Systems Control and Audit, Business Administration, Financial Regulation (CAS FinReg).

#### **CAREER HISTORY**



Swiss-CyberSecurity Information Technology-Services Switzerland Apr 2019–Feb 2020 Events coordinator (volunteer role)

Participated and contributed in the building of a community of cybersecurity professionals.



Saganà Switzerland

Jan 2015-current

Importation-distribution into Swiss market of certified organic coconut sweeteners **Business Analyst - Advisory Board member** (volunteer role)

Time period dedicated to Mar 2013–Dec 2014 my children's integration into Geneva community, and to language studies



Ralph Lauren Europe Switzerland

Aug 2012-Feb 2013

Sales Audit Assistant – Finance dpt. (temporary assignment)



Millennium Bank Greece - BCP Group

Oct 2002-Feb 2012

**Systems and Accounting Controller** – Finance dpt.

May 2005-Feb 2012

 Managed the reconciliation of interfaces between the core banking and accounting systems through SAP BusinessObjects Business Intelligence (BI) reports and AS/400 queries (systems: ICBS/Fiserv, OLYMPIC/Eri Bancaire, Atlas/Exodus)

Programmer Analyst – Information Technology dpt.

Oct 2002-Apr 2005

- Contributed in several projects from concept to completion, using the Systems Development Life Cycle (SDLC) approach, and the Waterfall model
- Reviewed business requirements, and created functional and technical specifications, project schedules, documentation, test plans, status reports, user support manuals, and training sessions
- Designed, developed and maintained banking applications (Salaries, Payrolls, Direct Debits, Clients Statements, Customer Relationship Management and Branch Teller applications)
- Trained internal users on SAP BusinessObjects Business Intelligence (historically BO/BOBJ) solution
- Provided 3rd level support for resolution of daily production issues

NL OF THE SECOND

### ING Bank Greece

May 1999-Sept 2002

**Programmer Analyst** – Information Technology dpt.

- Developed new banking applications while simultaneously maintained existing ones, by using RPG/400 programming language and SQL domain-specific language on AS/400 environment
- Resolved daily production issues while worked on electronic banking matters, underwriting, factoring, commissions, incentives and statistical data of agents
- Controlled ATMs' reconciliation in collaboration with First Data and DIAS organisations

Held diverse roles in Tourism, Publishing, Sales industries

Sept 1992-Aug 1997

#### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

IBM AS/400 System Programming
Online Computer Services S.A, Greece

1997-1999

Postgraduate Certificate - Information Technology-Business Administration
Piraeus University of Applied Studies, Greece

2002-2003

Certified Information Systems Auditor - CISA
Information Systems Audit and Control Association (ISACA)

2012

 Executive MBA - Master in Business Administration Studies Certificate University of Piraeus, Greece

2009-2011

□ Certificate of Advanced Studies in Financial Regulation (CAS FinReg)

Apr-Dec 2019

University of Geneva - University of Bern

## **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING & SEMINARS**

General Accounting

Banking Accounting

□ MiFID Framework & Auditing

Risk Based Internal Audit

International Financial Reporting Standards

SAP BusinessObjects Business Intelligence

□ RPG/400, RPG/ILE, CL, SQL

□ COBOL, Pascal, Visual Basic, Java, Python

□ OS/400, Mac OS, Windows

Microsoft Office applications

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Member of the Information Systems Audit and Control Association (ISACA)
- Member of the International Institute of Business Analysis (IIBA)

## LANGUAGES

□ **Greek** - Mother tongue

English - C1 level

□ French - B1 level

□ **German** - B1 level (primary school in Luzern)

□ Italian - A1